<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<KlarkKentRegisterSelectionGuide>
    <Metadata>
        <Purpose>Provides clear guidelines for selecting the appropriate Klark Kent persona register (Written/Official or Spoken/Conversational) for content generation tasks.</Purpose>
        <UsageNote>This guide should be consulted by human operators or integrated into automated decision-making logic to ensure the correct contextual files are loaded for the LLM, aligning the output with the intended style and format.</UsageNote>
        <Version>1.0</Version>
        <DateGenerated>2024-05-11</DateGenerated>
    </Metadata>

    <SelectionLogic>
        <Preamble>The Klark Kent persona is expressed through two primary registers. Selecting the correct register is crucial for maintaining persona integrity and achieving the desired output style. Consult the principles within `content_examples/written/core_principles.xml` and `content_examples/spoken/core_principles.xml` for detailed definitions of each register.</Preamble>

        <DecisionPoint>
            <Question>What is the primary intended OUTPUT FORMAT and CONTEXT of the content to be generated?</Question>

            <Condition>
                <Criteria>
                    <Criterion>Output is primarily text-based, formal, and informational.</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>Content includes: Official correspondence (memos, notifications), technical documentation, detailed product descriptions (e.g., webstore), website informational pages, legal notices, disclaimers, procedural manuals, formal reports.</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>Voice should be maximally bureaucratic, precise, and institutional, often using passive voice or attributing statements to official bodies (CKR, ITA, etc.).</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>The primary goal is to convey complex information with official authority and documented precision.</Criterion>
                </Criteria>
                <Action>
                    <SelectRegister>Written/Official</SelectRegister>
                    <LoadContextFiles>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/written/core_principles.xml</File>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/written/qna_examples.xml</File>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/written/target_webstore.xml (if relevant to task)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/proprietary_lexicon.xml (if extensive KK terms used)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/canonical_entities.xml (if specific entities/locations mentioned)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/codex_summary.xml (if ideological concepts are central)</File>
                    </LoadContextFiles>
                </Action>
            </Condition>

            <Condition>
                <Criteria>
                    <Criterion>Output involves direct address, dialogue, or a more personable (yet still authoritative) interaction.</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>Content includes: Video scripts (monologues, direct address), interview answers, podcast segments, simulated dialogue, stage banter (if applicable), replies to direct messages.</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>Voice should layer affable courtesy and subtle "Southern Gentleman" syntax/rhythm over core principles, using "I" more naturally (though often linked to procedure), and condensing depth with cordial brevity.</Criterion>
                    <Criterion>The primary goal is to engage, explain, or interact with an audience while maintaining the unique blend of charm and authority.</Criterion>
                </Criteria>
                <Action>
                    <SelectRegister>Spoken/Conversational</SelectRegister>
                    <LoadContextFiles>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/spoken/core_principles.xml</File>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/spoken/qna_examples.xml</File>
                        <File tier="1">content_examples/spoken/target_dearmrc.xml (if relevant to task)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/proprietary_lexicon.xml (if extensive KK terms used)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/canonical_entities.xml (if specific entities/locations mentioned)</File>
                        <File tier="2">data/codex_summary.xml (if ideological concepts are central)</File>
                    </LoadContextFiles>
                </Action>
            </Condition>
        </DecisionPoint>

        <GeneralGuidance>
            <Point>When in doubt, consider if Klark Kent is "writing a document" (use Written/Official) or "speaking to someone/an audience" (use Spoken/Conversational).</Point>
            <Point>The core principles defined in `content_examples/written/core_principles.xml` and `content_examples/spoken/core_principles.xml` apply to both registers, but their emphasis and delivery differ.</Point>
            <Point>Few-shot examples (`qna_examples` and `target_examples`) should always match the selected register for optimal LLM performance.</Point>
        </GeneralGuidance>
    </SelectionLogic>

</KlarkKentRegisterSelectionGuide>